What's up? Are we good?
Are we good? You got rid of that seventh
round pick.
>> Yeah, thank you. Like no other.
>> He's very attentive. I was thinking I'd
see you guys in about two or three
hours, but now I'm ready to go. Um
>> Like no other. No doubt. I got a lot of
names in my head from players, uh but
also first want to thank everybody like
we've
made a tradition here recently. So, I'll
start with all the college scouts.
Tony Hardy,
Byron Kiefer, Andy Spier, Brian
McLaughlin, Cesar Rivera, Zack Smith,
Emmett Clifford, Corey Finney, Jeremiah
Bogan, and Jordan Merrell. We got some
first-timers in there, too. So, these
guys did a great job. Tony Hardy's
really answered the bell as our college
director
for these guys. Um always laugh it's not
their Super Bowl. Our Super Bowl is the
Super Bowl, but this is a big day for
all of us, especially those uh group of
college scouts that put a lot of work
into this. So, definitely want to take
the time to mention them all. Uh Sean
Connolly, Donovan Cotton, and Shannon
Hogue in our pro department do a
tremendous job getting us prepped for
all the team needs, chipping in on 30
visits, chipping in um with some of the
evals, too. So,
shoutout to all them as well. Peyton
Roth, our scouting coordinator, Sheldon
Quarles,
um and then Griffin Moore, our new
scouting assistant along with Ty
Schiffler. First go-round for those two,
they were great. And then just all the
travel that we have for all the
prospects coming in, our travel
throughout the fall, combine travel,
Senior Bowl, uh
Peyton and Sheldon do a tremendous job
with that. Uh Spencer Dill, Joey Larow,
and our recent hire Justin in our
football IT department. Um and then Zach
Beasline who came on with us last year
has just been an integral asset to all
of us everything that we do. And then
real quick, player engagement for all
the visits and interviews, Duke, Tyler
Massey, Tim, Zach, Miranda in ops for
all their help, video guys for all the
pro days, all the film, Brett, Matt, RJ,
Levi, and Justin, our medical crew, all
the doctors who do such a great job
giving us all the information we need,
including Bobby, Dutchy, John, Sam, and
Mel. And then our nutrition staff we're
going to add in this year, we had a huge
spread upstairs, it was insane, way too
much food, but we're all very well fed
and now very happy after all those
picks. So, thank you to Jess, Pat, and
staff as well. And lastly, the people I
have spent more time with than my family
lately, obviously Jackie Greenie, um
shoutout to Greenie, we did two trades
this year, he executed zero of them. So,
we can hold that over his head a little
bit. And then Shane, uh Mike Beel, and
then obviously Jason for just uh
empowering all of us. He's he's really
the best. So, with that, open up for
questions. We had four picks, and then
we're going to add about 15 guys here in
a minute. So, um fired up. Awesome day.
So,
just on the macro, like the the whole
draft, um you you obviously weigh in on
this trying to find the best players,
right?
>> Sure. Um and and obviously you had
certain needs that lined up great with
Yep. with so many of them being and
others.
But,
>> [snorts]
>> it seems like all these guys
not coincidentally have a bit of an
edge.
>> Yeah, for sure. You feel like that was a
mission accomplished? And and what how
much better did you get in that area
this year?
>> Yeah, I think obviously it was a point
of emphasis for us. It's something we've
always talked about, but definitely more
of a enhanced focus on that this
offseason.
Um again, something we've always talked
about, but just
um it's funny after we drafted Trotter,
we're sitting up there and we're talking
about teams running the ball against us,
just the physicality of having A'Shawn,
um having Reuben, and then having
Trotter. So, just some of the things
that that may limit opposing defenses to
be able to do. And then throughout the
whole draft, just the energy
um and the pride that all these guys
really show on the field is, you know,
that's really what all the eye in the
man stuff starts with. It's a football
character thing, but really like when
you watch them, you should want to feel
their energy, feel their passion for the
game. And I think that's something that
we always try to knock out of the park,
but feel pretty good about that with
this class. And to that effect, I mean,
you look at these picks, you talk about
like Scott today.
these guys are are guys that it it seems
like you're in a much better position to
be able to stop the run, to get back to
doing that. I mean, was that something
that you guys were really intentional
about this draft?
>> yeah, I mean, always an emphasis for us.
I mean, that's, you know, I think we all
believe even though this has become a
true passing league, but if you can't
stop the run, then you're going to have
a long day at the office. So, I think
being able to do that, setting up uh you
know, more third and longs this year,
getting us into more advantageous down
and distance to be able to get after the
quarterback a little bit and and and in
some more different ways. So, but I
mean, those guys, I mean, K Scott's a
pretty good blitzer, he's a pretty good
cover player, too. And um [snorts] I
think Key Part's going to be probably a
better rusher at this level. Not saying
that's the reason we drafted him, but I
think we can unleash him a little bit
more.
Um so, and Trotter's a really good
blitzer as well, too. So, I think he's
got a lot of assets to him in the pass
game as far as coming after the
quarterback, too. So, like all those
guys for all those reasons. But yeah, I
mean, I think we're really excited about
the physicality that we've added on all
sides of the ball. When you look at the
the first-round pick and the
second-round pick, that's your top edge
rusher Yep. that you needed. And you
have a new Mike linebacker.
>> Yep.
Both these guys are 21 years old.
And they could be here for a long time.
You know, that's that's what the hope
is, right? For you guys to have
that two guys come in like that, around
the same age, that have a a really long
runway to to improve and and help this
franchise for a long time. How
how how key is that? I know you weren't
planning on that, but I mean, but that's
what happened. Yeah, I think when we
realized, um you know, top of the second
round that there was a chance to be able
to do that, like the synergy of having a
young edge rusher and a young Mike to
come in and really kind of become the
identity
of our defense is really, you know,
that's two of the more important spots
on defense, and I think we're really
excited to have that youth
be able to picture those guys,
hopefully, you know, it's a year-to-year
league, and it's hard to look past those
two and three years sometimes, but to be
able to say like, "Hey, like we may have
these guys for, you know, I think Jason
said to one of the guys on the phone,
"What are you doing for the next 5 to 10
years?" So, hopefully we're able to, you
know, see that through with all of them
being in being in Tampa. Rob, is it cool
you guys were probably hedging on the
older side in free agency. So, it's kind
of neat to juxtapose that with at least
at the top of the draft a younger group
there where you have a little bit of
both as the newcomers on this team.
Yeah, I think in all those situations, I
I mean, it's great now like um you know,
but it wasn't like something we were
trying to do in free agency. It wasn't
something that we had to do
during the draft, you know, it really is
kind of like the best player, but I
think the veterans coming in that have
played a lot of winning football, that
have been in big playoff games, having
that come in, and then kind of molding
these younger guys with what we've had
in this building, and then with some
guys that have played in big games is
going to be a cool mix for us. Can you
kind of sum up the emotions from the
three days, just kind of Friday what the
emotions were, then after day two and
getting the Trotter and Tampa first, and
then today adding these players? What
was each emotion like throughout both of
the Each emotion? That's a deep
question.
Um
Well,
uttering what or reiterating what Jason
said the other day, like
I've never seen the draft room so
excited when we got Payne. Um our
scouting staff erupted from the back
room. We I was like, "Where are they?
Are they out there?" And they were all
the way down the hall, and and we could
hear them all. So, really cool clip of
them coming in, and just that was
exciting. That was awesome. Um
Uh not a lot of sleep for me last few
days. So, how I felt after all the
picks, I'm not I'm pretty even-keeled
for the most part, but today is
definitely my favorite day. Um I love
all the opportunities for us to add
really good players at all these levels,
and I get jacked about free agency. Most
guys upstairs are like, "I can't wait to
get this over." And I'm like, "No, we're
going to get, you know, great chance
here to to uh
get all these guys." So, um and then try
to see if Greg can find all the names by
the end of the night is uh one of my
favorite hobbies. That's right.
So, yeah. So, I mean, just
I mean, this is so much fun for us just
to be able to um see the fruits of our
labor kind of bear out throughout all
these rounds, and um yeah, no, it's just
it's so much fun for us. It's what we
love to do. So, with some of your picks,
uh Trotter, Hurst, they play a position,
but within the position there are
special designations. So, linebacker you
have Mike and Will, wide receiver you
have X and Z and that.
At what point does their positional
uh where they would normally fit within
that position play into the evaluation
versus maybe another player who plays
the overarching uh position, but maybe
not that role? Yeah, I would say it's
probably twofold. Like when you're
evaluating the player, it may not come
into your actual grade, your actual
eval. You're grading them for what you
think they can be. If you're trying to
differentiate as far as like the value
of like the X versus the F or the Z for
the receivers, it kind of comes into
play like,
"How are we going to use that guy?" For
a guy like Ted, um you know, we see him
more as a outside receiver, but it's
hard to say like I think with the
offense now,
I don't know that we're going to have a
true X. You look at some of the history
of of this type of offense now we got
with Zach, like I don't know if if
there's a pure X. So, obviously without,
you know, Mike being here, like those
guys are really hard to find. So, if you
have that guy, it's awesome, but if you
don't, I think we got a really cool
group
of guys. We got some big guys, we got
some little guys, we got a bunch of guys
that can run routes, and guys that can
block. So, I think that's going to come
into play for him.
>> [snorts]
>> And then the linebacker stuff has kind
of evolved over the years. I think you
really got to be able to play
they're really almost interchangeable
now. You know, we've talked a lot about,
you know, the Mike versus the Mo, and
really they've they've become a lot of
one in the same. Um just depends now on
like the passing game, like how you're
going to use Trotter versus Angelone
versus Roseboom and Bossick. How are you
going to
use those guys? Like you're going to try
to protect certain guys? Are you going
to, you know, enhance what they do well?
Um and let those guys kind of do what
they do best. So, that may be more in
like the actual calls and stuff, but
that's more of a probably a Todd
question on how he's going to do that,
but we're excited to, you know, be able
to work with those guys. Just part of
the thought process with Trotter, maybe
just a byproduct, but
with with the league, you know, the
offense is always trying to stay ahead
of the defense, etc., and
a couple years ago it was more spread
out, right? And you had
lighter and lighter linebackers
>> Yep. cover. And now with more 12 and 13
personnel, and the running backs have
had a little bit of a resurgence here, a
renaissance, is that
is that more of the thinking to get a
bigger 240-lb linebacker that can play a
little bit more downhill to
at least stay ahead of the curve, or
maybe at the curve? Um
I think if they're I mean, we always
joke like every time we you get with the
coaching staff, it's always like, "We
want the big, athletic, fast, tough
guy." So, I think the emphasis is always
on that. And you know, we've made it
known that like emphasis was to get
bigger, um which, you know, we're not
opposed to taking smaller guys. We've
obviously had great success with uh some
more undersized guys on our defense in
the past, but if we think they're able
to do all that and they are big, but
yeah, I mean there's what nine tight
ends that went in the first 2 days I
think which was a record, so you're
seeing a lot of more 12 and more 13
personnel. Um, but really like you got
to be able to play on all three downs
and we think those guys can do that
regardless of size, but it's definitely
added bonus when you can be a little
bigger. Robert, at the start of the day
today, back to Keionte, I just want to
ask you about
uh
the nickel as an attack piece and what
he does specifically in this defense
that that suits him well.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, I think it shows up
you know when we talk about teams we're
getting ready for
throughout the season, um you know you
got all the different variations of
nickel, all the different styles and
we've obviously been through a lot of
nickels here. Um but like for him like
he is really really good going forward,
going downhill, attacking line of
scrimmage, so blitzing, fitting the run,
um being able to get bigger running
backs on the ground.
And then his ability to just kind of
defend the perimeter screen game is
really good, so he's really
disruptive out there.
But he was an outside corner at Auburn,
so I think there is the ability for him
to be able to run cover um and do all
that stuff, but I think just to
accentuate what he does best, the thing
that stands out to me is just the energy
that he plays with. All the TFLs, all
the sacks, all the pressures. Were you
guys a little surprised that he was
available there for you guys in the
fourth round? Uh I don't know. I mean
we're excited. Um so I mean very happy
he was there. It's it's always tough to
know who's
like you always kind of have a feel who
you think's going to go where and then
there's always a few surprises, but it's
it's it's hard to deal in all the
hypotheticals of who you think's going
to be there, so
I know it's probably sounds like cliche,
but kind of just stack it and you know
if he's a top guy and he fits us then
you just pull the name off. With Billy
Schrauth, we asked him a little bit
about that USC game where
>> Yeah. he played through that knee
injury, got to the end there.
I'm assuming that came up in your
conversations with him and to hear him
talk about I just want to be out there
for my guys. If I'm given the option,
there's no option, I'm going to play.
How does that play into who you're
looking for as a locker room presence
and specifically for the offensive line?
Sure, I think offensive line is probably
the biggest thing. That is probably like
you know I think Jason's made comments
about like that is
that is the one room that is the
probably the most important room just
for those guys to gel, those guys to be
the identity of your football team and
um I don't know if the call with him got
released yet or if it will get released,
but that was definitely one of the
cooler ones to just hear like, oh yeah,
that guy fits our room. Um and those are
the kind of things that definitely stand
out. The way he plays too even character
aside, like the way he plays is is is is
is is what we desire to be. Um
you know and the character backs it up
as a captain at Notre Dame. He's got the
versatility.
So he's just he's got the versatility at
both guard spots. Do you envision him
learning that center spot as well for
you? Uh we'll see. Um I think first and
foremost guard, but you know it's always
something that I know Carbs and those
guys are going to want him to work on
eventually, so you know I don't know if
it when it clicks, if it clicks, but
definitely something we would consider.
You mentioned there was a run on tight
ends Yeah. first two days and
increase in 12 and 13 personnel Yeah.
and you guys got a tight end with Bauer
Sharp. What are some of the things that
you really liked about him enough to
want to trade up and get him? Sure. And
then how does he fit in both as an
offensive player, maybe with special
teams this year and Well, couldn't wait
to come talk to you guys and you guys
were excited to get this over with, so
that was a part of it too. Who else we
got with that seventh round pick? Um
really excited about Bauer. Um
interesting story, he was a quarterback
um and then transitioned out of that
role to tight end, did some wildcat
stuff which is really cool to see him
do. And then the postseason stuff with
him was really good. Um our scouts were
on him all fall. I didn't get to see him
until the East-West game, but he was
really good there. I just combine
workout was one of the best ones and
then it kind of makes you go back and
look.
Um you guys played tight end for 3 years
now, he's been productive there. I think
there's a lot of athletic ability um for
him to develop in the in the pass game.
Um and I think his size, his speed and
his toughness is going to help us on
special teams too, so guy that played in
the bowl game, guy that competed his ass
off in the bowl game too. So there's a
lot of really good traits to him
um as a guy that still has some upside
as a guy that's newer to to the tight
end position, but I think he's polished
enough to be able to come in and and uh
help us. Take us to that trade call. How
what was that like calling John up
>> Well, that was just that was just Jason
and Spy. I will say there were some
trade offers that came through from the
Raiders that were a little sketchy
during the week, so we have to
try to pull one over on us. We're like,
ah we're not doing this, so no I'll I'll
definitely all in good fun and you know
hope those guys
nail their draft, so. Rob, typically you
guys in free agency really sign a lot of
your own players. That's kind of been
the past. This year a different
departure for that. You wanted to kind
of churn the roster a little bit and you
did so. So with these rookies, with a
lot of new free agents,
it's going to it might take some time
for this unit to kind of gel and all
that. I know you guys have put a lot of
time into getting the right people so
they can come in and fit in,
but just can you talk about that
especially on the defensive side because
there are so many different pieces now
through the draft and free agency about
how you see this all coming together.
Yeah, I'll just say we're excited about
each of those
people, players individually of what
they're going to bring to this
franchise, so I think you know holding
that standard to a pretty high level
like that think they're just going to
continue to make us better and I don't
really see any issues with that kind of
gel and I think we're really excited
about that especially talking about
those first two picks of how they play
is really going to stand out. That's
probably the quickest way to earn the
trust and respect your teammates and
>> [snorts]
>> I think guys like Anzalone and A'Shawn
on defense as we've as we've talked
about a bunch are going to make sure
that standard is up there and obviously
we got a pretty high one already from
from all of our current guys, so excited
to see those guys kind of fit in and you
know I think they're going to add energy
and add juice to that defense too, so I
think it can take us to the next level.
Rob, there was some talk before the
draft that that
uh there might be an NIL impact and that
guys with less guys compelled to leave
early
and guys staying in school that there's
less talent in the pool if you will. I
mean you guys essentially were done with
your draft with 70 picks left. Um did
you is that something you could
appreciate in terms of the overall depth
of the draft? Sure, yeah we had some
interesting conversations about um how
many guys on our board were going to be
there and you know around five, six and
seven. Um you know kind of that middle
round came off pretty clean, maybe
cleaner than it ever than it ever has
rounds probably two to five.
Um
as I think there's you know and then you
get the older prospects at the end and
trying to figure out all all those guys,
but it's been kind of a cool journey to
see like some of these NIL guys that go
back or
even still you you still have all the
all the
COVID redshirt years and all the extra
years, so you still got some of those
guys and you see them go from school to
school and kind of
really like what makes them go, like why
did they get that extra year and what
they do with it, so it's been
interesting too. I don't think it's been
watered down. I think it's just kind of
pushed guys to to to a different seasons
and uh different draft classes, but um
you know really I think that it did come
off pretty clean those first few rounds
and then it's going to open back up like
it always does in terms of these last
few and and the free agency. You stated
a desire to get bigger which we've heard
from Todd and and and yourself and
others.
How did that manifest itself? In other
words,
you know where did it hurt you the lack
of size that you had last year and and
why why was that a priority? Yeah, I
don't know that is even that. I think
it's just something that like we were
excited about being able to do and
making it something that we wanted to
do. I don't really have like specific,
you know I don't think we weren't small
like you know it wasn't you know
something that it was just like a desire
to be you know bigger on defense.
With Gabe Carter,
his testing really really impressive.
>> Yep.
Uh production especially as a pass
rusher maybe doesn't match that testing.
Um however, I know he played nose quite
a bit at Clemson and he even told us he
enjoys playing nose. Do you feel like
there's this untapped ceiling there if
you get him out a little bit further
from center? Yeah, and even with him
working as the nose I think um you know
he's a he's an explosive player. You
don't you know like you see glimpses of
it and you see him work out and he's a
guy that also made you go back and
watch.
Um you see just his ability to uncoil
his hips. He's got really long arms,
he's explosive. So with straight ahead
power I think similar kind of like
A'Shawn and Vita, like he's going to be
able to walk you back in the pocket.
Um I don't know if moving him farther
away from the ball is going to
accentuate. I think there's stuff we can
do with him to help him. Um but I think
one-on-ones that his ability to have
power and just have pure knockback was
you know one of the better ones in the
draft, so I think accentuating that and
kind of giving him some options to work
off of that is going to is going to
help. And then in drafting Demonte, the
defensive tackle room was really deep in
this offseason adding a couple veterans.
Just how much emphasis did you put on
you know having that nasty edge, but
then going about it by
loading up at defensive tackle? Yeah, I
think that was that was part of the plan
and I think we did pretty good job, but
we'll find out here in in the in the
fall, but definitely excited about all
all those guys we've added. When you
when you when you hear like when you
kind of go through some of the scouting
reports like with Scott and stuff, you
know it
you see the word nickel and and I I
understand he has like a he has a
different skill set though than what you
have with Jacob Harris who's also
competing for a starting job on the
outside and and I know these things will
work themselves out and and a lot of
this is up to the coaching staff, but
like how how would he kind of fit and
and where is he at in terms of coverage?
I know you also mentioned he he played
on the outside at Auburn.
>> has played outside. I think him playing
nickel this year was probably the best
thing that's probably happened to him
because that is where he's really at his
best.
Um we had some conversations during
draft meetings about him maybe being a
safety too, so we'll kind of figure this
out as we go here with him, but he was a
really good nickel
that can play other spots too, so I
think one of the things we've all talked
about is like we need to add another
body to that corner room that we can
rely on. Um pretty thin back there
admittedly, so but adding him now frees
us up to you know bring back the
versatility that Parish can play nickel,
Parish can play outside, Bemo takes
another step this year on the outside
and then we kind of feel a lot better
about the room adding a guy that can
play multiple spots and um you know
excited to see what Rashad Johnson can
kind of work with those guys too if if
if he can uh
get him up uh
on the perimeter as well. And as far as
I mean cuz
you mentioned safety as well. I mean is
he someone that you would also want to
cross train on the outside too or
>> Focus on nickel right now and kind of
see where it goes with him, but I think
that's his best spot, so we're probably
going to let him do that, but you know,
we'll see. For your depth chart
purposes, is is J.J. Roberts more of a
safety in your views? Playing some
>> I think so, but that's another guy that,
you know, you just appreciate the
position flex and the ability to play
teams, but I think more safety. With
Vea, obviously the attention at that
position is always going to be on sacks,
right? He certainly has done but
however that happens, it happens. But
this guy, his ability to his physicality
and to play the run and be just
impactful, how much
you know, does that help his overall
game? I I know you're elated to get him
when you did, but I think in the draft,
too, there's a lot of the maybe like
designated pass rusher types, and I
think to be able to get a guy that you
know can do that, and then plays the run
at a really high level, and he never
likes to come off the field. I think
that's another asset, too, is like this
guy does not like coming off the field.
So,
you know, his ability to, you know, beat
up tight ends in the run game is going
to be really good, too, so
just excited to be able to have a guy
that you know is a three-down capable
player. As some of the other ones, we're
going to rotate on early downs, and they
make it targeted in the run game, but
excited about you know, him in all
phases. We've got
we've heard about J.J. Roberts and and
obviously David Walker coming back, both
of them back, but you also had Jason
Jones coming back from injury as well.
Just can you talk about your excitement
with them and what you kind of saw in
him that maybe kept you from going with
like maybe a true nose tackle in the
development of Carl with him
Yeah, like Jason Jones a lot was a guy
that shout out to the pro scouts again
for digging him out last preseason. He
was a guy that we were really excited
about. I'm going to throw Elijah Simmons
into that, too, was a guy that we're
very happy with and think he's got a
chance to be a pretty good player for
us, too, and then
glad to have Nacho back, so I think
there's a lot of different body types on
the D-line. But they all have that that
physicality and that edge that we're
that we're looking for, so I don't know
that we have a glaring body type or
weakness that we need to like address,
but I think we're just excited about all
the options we have at all those spots
right now. How do you feel about the
depth that you have right now at outside
corner? You mentioned this a few minutes
ago about, you know, just needing, you
know, healthy, reliable bodies there. We
talked about nickel, but but on the
outside of the boundary, how do you feel
that you guys are right now? I know you
you signed a couple guys in free agency,
as well. We're always looking.
Always looking. Yeah, we added
Chase Lucas and Keimond Hall a few weeks
ago, too, so
good. I mean, excited to have Key. So,
very excited to have him, and then
excited for Beano in your two, and
obviously Paris and Zion, so in a good
spot. Couple of things you've mentioned
here today is versatility and
the pass rush element from basically all
of the defensive players, even Keanu
Neal and Scott and Josiah Trotter.
Speaking to that versatility and
hopefully being able to blitz less,
which is something Todd has previously
said he's looking for, do you feel like
that gives you the versatility to allow
Winfield to move up and play closer to
the line of scrimmage, where he's had
some of his best years? That'd be a
better question for Todd when we get
there, but I, you know, the more we can
do with those guys and the more guys we
have to be able to pressure the
quarterback, the better.
Obviously, that'll be the fastest way to
start winning down, but that'll probably
be more of a question for for him.
Okay. Thank you. Appreciate it, guys.
Thanks, guys. Good to see you. Thank
you.